东西都拿齐没
Have you got everything?
拿齐了 别担心
I've got everything. Don't worry.
保重
Be careful.
你得打电话给小茉…
You have to call Mo about...
噢 别管小茉了
Never mind Mo.
好了 那我走了 我爱你
Okay, I'm going now. I love you.
我爱你  -爱你
Love you.
我爱你 -再见
Love you . - Bye.
那么 我们要去哪儿
So where are we going?
一个我们从未去过的地方
Further than we've ever gone before.
这是5,000,000,023年
It's the year five billion and twenty-three.
我们在M87银河星系 这是…
We're in the galaxy M87 and this...
这是新地球
This is New Earth.
这…
ROSE: It's just...
这简直…
That's just...
不错吧 相当不错
Not bad. Not bad at all.
太神奇了
ROSE: That's amazing.
我永远不会习惯这样的 永远不会
I'll never get used to this, never.
踩在不一样的大地上 不一样的天空
Different ground beneath my feet. Different sky.
那是什么气味
What's that smell?
苹果草
Apple grass.
苹果草 -是的 -好美
Apple grass. - Yes - It's beautiful.
噢 我喜欢
Oh, I love this.
我只想说 和你一起旅行 我非常享受
Can I just say, travelling with you... I love it.
我也是
Me, too.
过来
Come on.
人类 她是纯种人类
Human! She's pure-blood human.
靠近点 靠近点
Closer, closer.
在50亿年时 太阳膨胀 炽烤着地球
So, the year five billion, the sun expands, the Earth gets roasted.
那是我们第一次旅行
That was our first date.
我们还吃了薯片
We had chips.
总之 地球完了 全变成了陨石和尘埃
So anyway, planet gone, all rocks and dust,
但是人类存活下去了 繁衍到各个星系
but the human race lives on, spread out across the stars.
当地球被太阳吞噬后 人类满怀乡愁
As soon as the Earth burns up, oh, they get all nostalgic.
在振作起来后 他们找到了这个地方
Big revival movement. They find this place.
一样的尺寸 一样的空气 一样的运行轨道 非常完美
Same size as the Earth, same air, same orbit, lovely.
消息传出去了 人类搬了进去
The call goes out, the humans move in.
这城市叫什么
What's the city called?
新纽约
New New York.
噢 少来了
Oh, come on.
是真的
It is!
这就是新纽约城
It's the City of New New York.
严格地来说 这已经是第15个纽约了
Strictly speaking, it's the fifteenth New York since the original.
所以应该叫做
So that makes it
新新新新……纽约
New New New New New New New New New New New New New New New York.
怎么了 - 你很不一样
What ? - You are so different.
新新博士
New new Doctor.
不可能 我认识那个孩子
CASSANDRA: Impossible! I recognise that child.
她的脸 给我看看她的脸
Her face! Show me her face!
近点 近点
Closer, closer.
脸 脸 脸
Face, face, face!
我们去看看这个新纽约有多好 好到他们起了两次名字
Can we go and visit New New York? So good they named it twice.
然而 我觉得我们应该先到那儿去一趟
Well, I thought we might go there first.
为什么 那是什么
Why? What is it?
某种医院
Some sort of hospital.
旁边的绿色月亮 那是宇宙通用的医院标志
Green moon on the side, that's the universal symbol for hospitals.
我收到这个 通灵纸片上有封信息
I got this. A message on the psychic paper.
有人想见我
Someone wants to see me.
噢 我以为我们是来观光的
Oh, and I thought we were just sightseeing.
进去吧 我们去买些葡萄吧
Come on, then, let's go and buy some grapes.
噢 洛斯·泰勒 我就知道
Rose Tyler! I knew it!
那个下流的金发女杀手
That dirty blonde assassin.
她正往这里来 主人
She's coming here, mistress.
这不仅仅是巧合那么简单 这是命运
But this is beyond coincidence. This is destiny.
终于 我可以向这小贱人复仇…
At last, I can be revenged on that little...
太刻薄了吧 你说这话
A bit rich coming from you.
我也没办法 我不喜欢医院 总是让我不寒而栗
I can't help it. I don't like hospitals. They give me the creeps.
愿望花园现开放访问
The pleasure gardens will now take visitors
接下来15分钟的 携带绿色或蓝色识别卡的访客
carrying green or blue identification cards for the next 15 minutes.
请不要在花园里横穿
Visitors are reminded that cuttings from the gardens are not permitted.
好漂亮 不像是国家医疗中心
Very smart. Not exactly NHS.
没有商店 我喜欢小商店
No shop. I like the little shop.
我以为在这么远的未来 所有的病都被治愈了呢
I thought this far in the future, they'd have cured everything.
人类在发展 但是病毒也在进化 这是一场持久的战争
The human race moves on, but so do the viruses. It's an ongoing war.
希望 融洽 健康
Hope, harmony and health.
他们是猫
They're cats.
好 不要盯着人家
Now, don't stare.
想想你在他们眼里有多奇怪 又红又黄的
Think what you look like to them. All pink and yellow.
如果是我 我会把商店设在那里
That's where I'd put the shop, right there.
26号房 谢谢
Ward 26, thanks.
接管控制
Override controls.
等等 等等
Hold on, hold on!
不行 太迟了 我上去了
Oh, too late. I'm going up.
没事 我坐另一辆电梯
All right, there's another lift.
26号房
Ward 26!
小心消毒剂
And watch out for the disinfectant.
小心什么
Watch out for what?
消毒剂
The disinfectant!
什么
The what?
消…噢 你到时侯就知道了
The dis... Oh, you'll find out.
26号房 谢谢
Ward 26, thanks.
‘开始消毒第一步’
Commence stage one disinfection.
人类小孩干净了
The human child is clean.
呃 我在找26号房
Erm, I'm looking for ward 26.
这边 洛斯·泰勒
This way, Rose Tyler.
地方不错
Nice place.
不过楼下没商店 我觉得应该有一个 不用很大 一小个就行
No shop downstairs. I'd have a shop. Not a big one, just a shop.
方便人们买东西
So people can shop.
医院是治疗的地方
The hospital is a place of healing.
商店对一些人很有好处的 不是我 是别的人
A shop does some people the world of good. Not me, other people.
"修女互助会"终生承诺帮助和医治他人
The Sisters of Plenitude take a lifelong vow to help and to mend.
抱歉
Excuse me!
普通人如果想见曼哈顿公爵一面
Members of the public may only gaze upon the Duke of Manhattan
必须要有新纽约参议院的书面证明
with written permission from the Senate of New New York.
那是逆向石化症 是吗
That's petrifold regression, right?
我要死了 先生
I'm dying, sir.
终身致力于慈善 却落得这样的下场
A lifetime of charity and abstinence and it ends like this.
曼哈顿公爵所说的任何一句话
Any statements made by the Duke of Manhattan
没有官方允许不得公开
may not be made public without official clearance.
弗洛·克洛维斯
Frau Clovis...
我好虚弱
I'm so weak.
洁特修女 给我们一点隐私 好吗
Sister Jatt, a little privacy, please.
他马上就能起来了
He'll be up and about in no time.
我很怀疑
I doubt it.
逆向石化症 他快要变成石头了 再过一千年也不会有治疗方法
Petrifold regression, he's turning to stone. There won't be a cure for a thousand years.
他也许很快就能起来 但而只能作为一尊石像了
He might be up and about but only as a statue.
请对修女团体有点信心
Have faith in the Sisterhood.
但在这里有没有你认识的人
But is there no one here you recognise?
来医院却不是为了探访病人 这是不太寻常的
It's rather unusual to visit without knowing the patient.
不是的 我想我找到他了
No, I think I've found him.
海姆修女 能否请你替我招待一下这位先生
Novice Hame, if I can leave this gentleman in your care.
噢 我的朋友迷路了 洛斯·泰勒 能在接待处帮我问一下吗
Oh, I think my friend got lost. Rose Tyler. Could you ask at reception?
当然可以 先生
Certainly, sir.
恐怕伯欧之脸睡着了 -这些天他几乎都在睡觉
I'm afraid the Face of Boe is asleep. That's all he tends to do these days.
你们是朋友
Are you a friend, or...
我们只见过一次 在一号月台 他怎么了
We met just the once. On Platform One. What's wrong with him?
我很抱歉 我以为你知道
I'm so sorry. I thought you knew.
伯欧之脸快要死了
The Face of Boe is dying.
因为什么
Of what?
年老 这是我们唯一不能治愈的
Old age. One thing we can't cure.
他已经几千岁了 还有人说是几百万岁
He's thousands of years old, some people say millions,
尽管那是不可能的
although that's impossible.
噢 我不知道 我喜欢不可能
Oh, I don't know. I like impossible.
我来了 虽然样子变了 但还是我
I'm here. I look a bit different, but it's me.
我是博士
It's the Doctor.
看我
MAN: Look at me!
这不是很奇妙吗
Isn't it wonderful?
你永远不会知道自己的命运将走向何方 不会
Well, you never know what your life is going to be like, ever.
我喝够了这个饮料 总之…
I'm bored with this drink. Anyway...
噢 你好亲爱的 别乱来 别这样
Oh, hello, darling. Oh! Now don't. Stop it.
等等 那是…
Wait a minute. That's...
躲躲猫
Peek-a-boo!
你不要靠近我 卡桑德拉
Don't you come anywhere near me, Cassandra.
为什么 你认为我能干嘛 把你弹死吗
Why? What do you think I'm going to do? Flap you to death?
说得没错 但是这个咕噜呢
Yeah, but what about Gollum?
噢 那是阿奇 他是我的宠物
Oh, that's just Chip. He's my pet.
我崇拜主人
I worship the mistress.
给我保湿 给我保湿
Moisturise me, moisturise me.
严格来说不算是一个生物体 他是一个强制生长的克隆体
He's not even a proper life form. He's a force-grown clone.
我把他塑造成我喜欢的模样
I modelled him on my favourite pattern.
他对我非常忠诚
But he's so faithful.
阿奇负责我的身理需求
Chip sees to my physical needs.
希望那是指食物 -你怎么还活着
I hope that means food. How come you're still alive?
在你谋杀了我之后
After you murdered me?
那是你咎由自取
That was your own fault.
我主人的大脑幸存下来
The brain of my mistress survived.
还有她漂亮的蓝眼睛 都从容器里抢救过来了
And her pretty blue eyes were salvaged from the bin.
那皮肤呢
What about the skin?
我亲眼看到的 你裂成了碎片
I saw it. You got ripped apart.
那块皮肤取自我身体的前部
That piece of skin was taken from the front of my body.
这是背部的那一块皮
This piece is the back.
好 所以你在用你的…
Right, so you're talking out of your...
别多嘴
Ask not!
我主人大难不死 阿奇把主人隐藏在医院里
The mistress was lucky to survive. Chip secreted m‘lady into the hospital.
所以他们不知道你们在这里
So they don't know you're here?
阿奇偷取药品
Chip steals medicine.
帮助了我的主人 减轻她的痛苦
Helps m'lady. Soothes her.
安抚她
Strokes her.
不用再说下去了 阿奇
You can stop right there, Chip.
但我很孤独 一个人躲在这里
But I'm so alone, hidden down here.
世上最后的人类
The last human in existence.
别又开始那套
Don't start that again.
这里已经是新地球了
They've called this planet New Earth.
一块蔬菜地
A vegetable patch.
那里有着成千上万的人类 成千上万
And there's millions of humans out there, millions of them.
变种货
Mutant stock.
他们进化了 卡桑德拉 人类本来就应该进化
They evolved, Cassandra, they just evolved. Like they should.
你原地踏步 你把自己泡在罐子里封存起来
You stayed still, you got yourself all pickled and preserved,
这对你有什么好处
and what good did it do you?
我记得那天晚上 特雷斯大使的酒会
I remember that night. Drinks for the Ambassador of Thrace.
那是最后一次有人夸我漂亮
That was the last time anyone told me I was beautiful.
那之后 生活变得艰难起来
After that, it all became such hard work.
你的生存能力确实很强 我承认
You've got a knack for survival, I'll give you that.
但我并没有在虚度光阴 洛斯 隐匿在这医院之下
But I've not been idle, Rose. Tucked away, underneath this hospital,
我一直在打探 修女组织在隐藏着什么
I've been listening. The Sisters are hiding something.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
那些猫有着不可告人的秘密
These cats have secrets.
安静 让我小声告诉你 靠近点
Hush. Let me whisper, come close.
你是不是在说笑 别以为我会靠近你半步
You must be joking if you think I'm coming anywhere near you.
阿奇 激活心灵移植器
Chip! Activate the psycho-graft!
我动不了 卡桑德拉 放开我
I can't move. Cassandra, let me go!
你在干吗
What are you doing?
我也懂得变化
The lady's moving on.
再见了蹦床 我来了金发女
It's goodbye trampoline and hello blondie!
主人
Mistress.
给我保湿
Moisturise me.
多奇异啊 手臂
How bizarre. Arms.
手指
Fingers!
头发
Hair!
我看看 我看看
Let me see, let me see.
噢 上帝
Oh, my God!
我是个不良少女
I'm a chav.
希望 融洽 健康
Hope, harmony and health.
你真好 不必这样的
That's very kind. There's no need.
你一直在工作
You're the one working.
也没什么太多的事情
There's not much to do.
只是维持他的空气而已
just maintain his smoke.
我认为我是他的伙伴 我有时能听到他的歌声
And I suppose I'm company. I can hear him singing sometimes,
在我脑海里
in my mind.
那些古老的歌曲
Such ancient songs.
我是唯一的访客
Am I the only visitor?
伯欧族的其他成员在很久之前就灭绝了
The rest of Boekind became extinct long ago.
他是最后一个了
He's the only one left.
传说伯欧之脸见证了宇宙的成长
Legend says that the Face of Boe has watched the universe grow old.
有着各种各样的关于他的传说
There's all sorts of superstitions around him.
其中一个说的是 在他死之前
One story says that just before his death,
伯欧之脸会透露他的大秘密
the Face of Boe will impart his great secret.
他只会给一个像他一样的人吐露秘密
That he will speak those words only to one like himself.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
这只是个传说而已
It's just a story.
告诉我其余的部分
Tell me the rest.
传说他会告诉一个流浪者 一个无家可归的人
It's said he'll talk to a wanderer. To the man without a home.
孤独的主
The lonely god.
看看我 从头到尾
Look at me. From class to brass.
尽管…
Although...
噢
Ooh.
曲线… 噢 亲爱的
Curves. Oh, baby!
这就像生活在一个有弹性的堡垒里
It's like living inside a bouncy castle.
主人好漂亮啊
The mistress is beautiful.
当然了
Abs0lument.
噢 但你看
Oh, but look.
这脑浆没用了
Aw, the brain meat expired.
我的老主人完了
My old mistress has gone.
不过她在这里 安然无恙
But safe and sound in here.
那个小孩洛斯的意识怎么办
But what of the Rose child's mind?
藏起来了 我只能靠近记忆的表层 她…
Tucked away. I can just about access the surface memory. She's...
糟了 她是和博士一起来的
God, she's with the Doctor.
那个人 他就是博士
That man, he's the Doctor.
同一个博士 换了张新脸
The same Doctor with a new face!
那个伪君子…
That hypocrite!
我必须知道给他做手术的医生是谁
I must get the name of his surgeon.
我也需要做做调整 尽管…
I could do with a little work. Although...
屁股挺丰满的
nice rear bumper.
噢 这玩意好像在响 难道是坏了吗
Oh! It seems to be ringing. Is it meant to ring?
这是一种原始的通信设备
A primitive communications device.
洛斯 跑哪去啦
DOCTOR: Rose, where are you?
她是怎么说话的
How does she speak?
旧地球的伦敦腔
Old Earth cockney.
恩…
Urn...
怎么啦
Wotcha.
你去哪儿了 去26号怎么花了这么久
Where have you been? How long have you take to get to warp 26 ?
我在路上了 老板
I'm on my way, guv'nor.
我要把苹果和梨子吃掉
I shall proceed up the apples and pears.
你绝对猜不到 我见到伯欧之脸了 还记得他吗
You'll never guess! I'm with the Face of Boe. Remember him?
当然记得了
Of course I do.
那又大又老的…伯欧族
That big old...boe race.
我得走了 一会儿见
I'd better go. See you in a minute.
真想不到我能恢复
I didn't think I was going to make it.
又是那个人 他是我的幸运魔法
It's that man again! He's my good luck charm.
过来 别害羞
Come in! Don't be shy.
曼哈顿公爵的任何友好问候
Any friendship expressed by the Duke of Manhattan
都不能构成合法的合约
does not constitute a form of legal contract.
把床调起来
Winch me up!
啊 看着我 没有感染的迹象
Up! Look at me. No sign of infection.
要香槟吗 先生
Champagne, sir?
不用了 谢谢
No, thanks.
你得的是逆向石化症 是吧
You had petrifold regression, right?
要用“曾经得过”才对
"Had" being the operative word.
已经过去了
Past tense!
完全康复了
Completely cured.
但那是不可能的
But that's impossible.
原始的种族恐怕会指责我们施了魔法
Primitive species would accuse us of magic
但这只不过是对科学的简单运用而已
but it's merely the tender application of science.
你们到底是怎样治好他的
How on earth did you cure him?
应该说新地球
How on New Earth, you might say.
溶液里有什么
What's in that solution?
简单的药物
A simple remedy.
告诉我那是什么
Then tell me what it is.
抱歉 这是病人的保密资料
I'm sorry. Patient confidentiality.
我们还没见过面吧 我叫梅特伦·卡斯帕
I don't believe we've met. My name is Matron Casp.
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
你得明白在这里我们才是医生
I think you'll find that we are the doctors here.
梅特伦·卡斯帕  你需要到深切护理室一趟
Matron Casp, you're needed in intensive care.
请原谅我告辞了
If you would excuse me.
这又发生了 又有一病人出现意识了
It's happened again. One of the patients is conscious.
我们不能坐视不管
Well, we can't have that.
这个博士是个危险人物
This Doctor man is dangerous.
危险且聪明
Dangerous and clever.
我也许需要一个他那样的头脑 修女团体正在密谋什么
I might need a mind like his. The Sisterhood is up to something.
老话说得好
Remember that old Earth saying?
修女不可信 护士不可信
"Never trust a nun, never trust a nurse...
猫更不可信
and never trust a cat."
香水
Perfume?
当时正在进行正常的血液清洗
It was having a perfectly normal blood-wash,
然后突然之间 它开始哭起来 就是这个
then all of a sudden it started crying. It's this one.
请…
Please.
看它的眼睛 多活泼
Look at its eyes.- So alive.
积极地闪烁着
Positively sparkling.
请问 我在哪
Please. - Where am I?
还会说话
And speech.
它是怎么会懂得词汇
How can it even have a vocabulary?
卡文修女写了篇关于语句迁移的论文
Sister Corvin has written a thesis on the migration of sentience.
她称之为"生命回音" 可以去读一读
She calls it The Echo of Life. It's well worth a read.
帮我
Help me.
我看够了 谢谢
I've seen enough, thank you.
如果这再发生 我们可能必须回去重修脑干政策了
If this happens again, we might have to review our brainstem policy.
我们该怎么处置那病人
And what should we do with the patient?
标准程序 焚毁
Standard procedure. Incinerate.
你来了 过来看看这个病人
There you are. Come and look at this patient.
马科尼氏病 本应花上好几年才能康复
Marconi's disease. Should take years to recover.
两天 我没见过这样的事
Two days. I've never seen anything like it.
他们发明了细胞冲洗喷流 太神奇了
They've invented a cell-washing cascade. It's amazing.
他们的医学科技过于先进 还有这个
Their medical science is way advanced. And this one.
帕里多姆潘克罗西斯病 10分钟就能置人于死地 但他没事
Pallidome pancrosis. Kills you in ten minutes, and he's fine.
我得去找个终端 看看他们是怎么做到的
I need to find a terminal. I've got to see how they do this.
如果他们有世界上最好的药 为什么会这么神秘
'Cause if they've got the best medicine in the world, then why is it such a secret?
我不能亚当夏娃这事
I can't Adam and Eve it.
什么… 你的声音怎么了
What...What's with the voice?
我不知道 只是在乱说
I don't know, just larking about.
新的地球
New Earth.
新的我
New me.
那我也会说啊 新新博士
Well, I can talk. New new Doctor.
恩 你不正是吗
Mmm, aren't you just?
终端设备在这边
Terminal's this way.
是的 魅力依然不减
Yeah, still got it.
没有 没什么奇怪的 手术室 术后恢复室
No, nothing odd. Surgery. Post-op.
纳米牙医室
Nanodentistry.
没有商店的踪迹 他们应该有有间商店
No sign of a shop. They should have a shop.
不 这里缺少别的什么
No, it's missing something else.
当时我在楼下 那些修女护士猫
When I was downstairs, those nurse-cat-nuns
在谈论深切治疗 但在哪儿呢
were talking about intensive care, but where is it?
你是对的 做得好
You're right. Well done.
他们为什么要隐藏起整个部门
Why would they hide a whole department?
一定在某个地方 搜索一下大楼结构
It's got to be there somewhere. Search the subframe.
如果大楼结构被锁定了呢
What if the subframe‘s locked?
试一下安装协议
Try the installation protocol.
是的 当然了 抱歉
Yeah. Course. Sorry.
深切治疗…
Intensive care.
看着确实挺深的
Certainly looks intensive.
好恶心 他是怎么回事
That's disgusting. What's wrong with him?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
那是什么病
What disease is that?
所有的病
All of them.
这个星系里的每种疾病 他们都感染上了
Every single disease in the galaxy. They've been infected with everything.
那我们呢 我们安全吗
What about us? Are we safe?
空气消过毒 只要不碰他们就行了
The air's sterile. just don't touch them.
这里有多少病人
How many patients are there?
他们不是病人
They're not patients.
但他们有病
But they're sick.
他们生来就有病
They were born sick.
他们就是疾病 他们存在就为了得病
They're meant to be sick. They exist to be sick.
实验室的老鼠
Lab rats.
怪不得修女能治疗一切
No wonder the Sisters have got a cure for everything.
他们建了终极研究实验室
They've built the ultimate research laboratory.
人类农场
A human farm!
为什么他们没死
Why don't they just die?
瘟疫容器 最后才能死
Plague carriers. The last to go.
这是为了更好的目标
It's for the greater cause.
海姆修女
Novice Hame.
当你发了誓言时 你会同意这样做吗
When you took your vows, did you agree to this?
修女团体承诺过要去帮助
The Sisterhood has sworn to help.
什么 用杀生的方式
What, by killing?
但他们不是真正的人
But they're not real people.
他们是特别培养的 他们不是完整的存在
They're specially grown. They have no proper existence.
营业额是多少
What's the turnover?
每天一千个 一千又一千 有多少千了
A thousand a day? Thousand the next? Thousand the next? How many thousands?
多少年了 多少
For how many years? How many?
人类需要我们
Mankind needed us.
他们带着许多疾病来到这个星球 我们无法应对
They came to this planet with so many illnesses, we couldn't cope.
我们试过了 我们试过所有办法
We did try. We tried everything.
我们用过克隆肉和生化牛
We tried using clone meat and bio-cattle,
但效果都很缓慢
but the results were too slow.
所以 修女团体自主培养了人体
So the Sisterhood grew its own flesh.
他们就是肉体而已
That's all they are. Flesh.
这些人都是活的
These people are alive.
想想外面那些人
But think of those humans out there,
健康 幸福 都是因为我们
healthy, and happy, because of us.
如果他们靠这个而活着 那生命还有什么意义
If they live because of this then life is worthless.
但你是谁 凭什么这样决定
But who are you to decide that?
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
如果你不满意 如果你想先向高层反映 那没有了
And if you don't like it, if you want to take it to a higher authority, there isn't one.
在我这里停止
It stops with me.
只是想确定一下
just to confirm...
这城市里没有人知道这事
none of the humans in the city actually know about this?
我们觉得最好不要…
We thought it best not...
等等 我能明白那些躯体
Hold on. I can understand the bodies,
我能理解你们的誓言
I can understand your vows,
但有一件事我不明白
but one thing I can't understand.
你对洛斯做了什么
What have you done to Rose?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
我正在努力保持冷静
And I'm being very, very calm.
你需要知道这点 非常非常冷静
You want to be aware of that. Very, very calm.
我保持很冷静的唯一理由就是
And the only reason I'm being so very, very calm
大脑是个很脆弱的东西
is that the brain is a delicate thing.
不管你对洛斯做了什么 我要你把她复原
Whatever you've clone to Rose's head, I want it reversed.
我们什么都没做过
We haven't done anything.
我很好呀
I'm perfectly fine.
这些人快要死了 而洛斯会在乎他们
These people are dying and Rose would care.
好吧 算你聪明 机灵鬼
All right, clever clogs. Smarty-pants.
少女杀手
Ladykiller.
你怎么了
What's happened to you?
我知道这医院正在密谋些什么
I knew something was going on in this hospital
但我需要这躯体 和你的头脑去进行调查
but I needed this body and your mind to find it out.
你是谁
Who are you?
最后的人类
The last human.
卡桑德拉
Cassandra?
醒过来了就闻闻这香水
Wake up and smell the perfume.
你伤害他
You've hurt him.
我不明白 我不得不把护士长找来
I don't understand. I'll have to fetch Matron.
去吧 因为我正想见她
You do that 'cause I want to see her.
赶快跑 启动警报
Now run along! Sound the alarm!
护士长 是那个男人和那个女孩
Matron, it's that man and the girl.
我们听见警报了
We heard the alarm.
你先回去工作 照顾你的病人
Now, get back to work. Tend to your patients.
放我出去 放我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
你不觉得很幸运吗 还有空位 唯一的空余
Aren't you lucky there was a spare? Standing room only.
你偷了洛斯的身体
You've stolen Rose's body!
多年来 我想了上千种办法来杀你 博士
Over the years, I've thought of a thousand ways to kill you, Doctor.
现在全都实现了 上千种疾病正等着你
And now that's exactly what I've got. One thousand diseases.
他们每10分钟就会把毒素排向这些病人
They pump the patients with a top-up every 10 minutes.
你只剩3分钟时间了
You've got about three minutes left.
好好享受
Enjoy.
放了洛斯吧 卡桑德拉
just let Rose go, Cassandra.
我会的
I will.
只要我找到一个更年轻…更特别的
As soon as I find someone younger and less common.
然后我会把她当垃圾扔掉 现在 乖乖睡
Then I'll junk her with the waste. Now hush-a-bye.
表演时间到了
It's showtime.
有什么需要帮助的吗
Anything we can do to help?
我就直说吧 小胡须 我要钱
Straight to the point, whiskers. I want money.
我们是慈善机构 我们不给钱 只接受
The Sisterhood is a charity, we don't give money. We only accept.
人们不远万里来给你们钱
The humans across the water pay you a fortune,
而那正是我需要的
and that's exactly what I need.
一次性支付 这就是我的要求
A one-off payment, that's all I want.
或者加一条游艇 而作为回报
Oh, and perhaps a yacht, in return for which
我不会向这个城市提起你们的制度性谋杀
Iwill tell the city nothing of your institutional murder.
同意吗
Is that a deal?
恐怕不行
I'm afraid not.
我真的建议你们考虑一下
I'd really advise you to think about this.
不用了 我必须拒绝
Oh, there's no need. I have to decline.
我会公之于众 你别想阻止我
I'll tell them. And you've no way of stopping me.
你们修女又没有枪 甚至连武器都没有
You're not exactly nuns with guns. You're not even armed.
我们不需要武器 我们有爪子
Who needs arms when we have claws?
噢 行不通…阿奇 B计划
Well, nice try. Chip, plan B!
你干了什么
What have you done?
给系统打了一针肾上腺素 好让他们醒过来 再见
Gave the system a shot of adrenalin, just to wake them up. See ya!
别碰他们 无论如何 千万别碰他们
Don't touch them! Whatever you do, don't touch!
请救救我们 救救我们
WOMAN: Save us.
我看我们应该撤退
I think we should withdraw.
我们知道你们对我们做了什么
We understood what you did to us.
作为机器的一部分 我们了解机器
As part of the machine, we know the machine.
有意思 它们已经懂得建立论点了
Fascinating. It's actually constructing an argument.
而我们会结束它
And we will end it.
救救我们
Save us.
他们自由了
They're free.
圣托里女神在上
By the goddess Santori!
那些肉体自由了
The flesh is free!
停止痛苦
Stop the pain.
噢 天呐
ROSE: Oh, my God!
看看你们到底做了什么
What the hell have you done?
不是我
It wasn't me.
碰一下 你就会得到世上所有的疾病
One touch and you get every disease in the world.
我需要保证这个躯体的安全 卡桑德拉 我们得下去
And I want that body safe, Cassandra. We've got to go down.
但他们成千上万
But there's thousands of them.
下 下 下去
DOCTOR: Down, down, go down!
隔离大楼
Quarantine the building!
本大楼已隔离
This building is under quarantine.
重复 本大楼已隔离
Repeat, this building is under quarantine.
任何人不得离开这栋建筑
No one may leave the premises.
重复 任何人不得离开这栋建筑
Repeat, no one may leave the premises.
继续跑 下去
DOCTOR: Keep going! Go down!
救我 救救我们
Help us. Save us.
救我…
Help me!
不行的 电梯关闭了 大楼已经隔离 一切都不能运作
No, the lifts have closed down. There's a quarantine, nothing's moving.
这边
This way!
噢 他会被碰到的
Someone would touch him.
别管他 他是克隆体 只有半条命 快走
Leave him! This is a clone thing. He's only got a half-life. Come on!
主人
Mistress!
抱歉 我不能让她逃了
I'm sorry, I can't let her escape.
我的主人
My mistress!
打扰了 能来人帮帮忙吗
Excuse me, can we get some service?
我们被困了 接下来怎么做
We're trapped! What are we going to do?
首先 你必须离开她的身体
Well, for starters, you're going to leave that body.
心灵移植器是禁止的 在任何有居民的星球
That psycho-graft is banned on every civilised planet.
你快把洛斯挤死了
You're compressing Rose to death.
但我没地方可去
But I've got nowhere to go.
我原来的皮肤死了
My original skin's dead.
不关我的事 你可以像原子漂浮在空气中 现在出来
Not my problem. You can float as atoms in the air. Now get out.
把她还给我
Give her back to me.
你自找的
You asked for it.
噢 我的头
Blimey, my head.
她去哪儿了
Where did she go?
天呐 这…不一样
Oh my, this is...different.
卡桑德拉
Cassandra?
天呐 我是个男人
Goodness me, I'm a man.
哇哦 好多部件 基本都是新的
Yum. So many parts. And hardly used.
啊 啊 两颗心脏
Oh! Ah! Two hearts!
噢 宝贝 我在用心脏跳桑巴
Oh, baby, I'm beating out a samba.
从他身上出来
Get out of him!
喔 他很苗条
Ooh, he's slim.
还有点妖媚
And a little bit foxy.
你也这么想 我也进过你的大脑
You thought so, too. I've been inside your head.
你一直在偷看
You've been looking.
你喜欢…
You like it.
我们怎么办 他会怎么做 博士 他到底会做什么
What do we do? What would he do? The Doctor! What the hell would he do?
梯子 我们爬上去
Ladder. We've got to get up.
别挡路 金发妞
Out of the way, blondie!
求你了 帮帮我们
Please! Help us!
如果你离开博士的身体 他就能想到办法
If you get out of the Doctor's body, he can think of something.
天呐 在你脑子里真够乏味 激素城市
God, it was tedious inside your head. Hormone city.
我们会死的 如果…
But we're gonna die if... Ow!
放开
Get off!
我们所做的一切 所有的治疗
All our good work. All that healing.
修女团体的名誉 全都被你毁了
The good name of the Sisterhood. You have destroyed everything!
回去玩你的毛线球吧
Go and play with a ball of string.
四处都是疾病
Everywhere, disease.
这就是人类世界 疾病的世界
This is the human world. Sickness!
快爬
Move!
完全隔离 所有飞行器请改道
Maximum quarantine. Divert all shuttles.
帮帮我们
Help us.
现在我们该怎么做
Now what do we do?
用音速起子
Use the sonic screwdriver.
你是说这个东西
You mean this thing?
是的 就是那东西
Yes, I mean that thing!
但我不知道怎么用 博士把所有思维都隐藏起来
But I don't know how! That Doctor's hidden away all his thoughts.
卡桑德拉 快回到我身上 博士能打开门
Cassandra, go back into me. The Doctor can open it.
快
Do it!
抓紧了
Hold on tight.
噢 又变回不良少女了
Oh, chav-tastic again.
把门打开
Open it!
除非你离开她
Not till you get out of her!
我们需要博士
We need the Doctor.
我命令你离开他
I order you to leave her!
不管情况有多艰难 也没必要大叫
No matter how difficult the situation, there is no need to shout.
卡桑德拉 离开他
Cassandra, get out of him!
但如果我去你那儿 他直接就拒绝了 他真没礼貌
But if I go into you, he simply refuses. He's so rude.
我不管 做点事
I don't care, just do something!
我一定会后悔这样做的
Oh, I'm so going to regret this.
我的神啊 我看起来好恶心
Oh, sweet Lord! I look disgusting.
你回来真好
Nice to have you back.
不 你别想
No, you don't.
警告你这是最后一次 卡桑德拉
That is your last warning, Cassandra.
在她的脑袋里…
Inside her head...
他们好孤单
They're so alone.
他们一直伸手只是为了抓住我们
They keep reaching out, just to hold us.
他们一生 都不曾被触碰过
All their lives and they've never been touched.
我们是安全的 我们没感染 看呐 看呐
We're safe, we're safe, we're safe! We're clean, we're clean! Look, look.
给我看看你们的皮肤
Show me your skin.
看 没感染 看
Look! Clean! Look!
如果我们被碰了 我们早就死了
If we'd been touched, we'd be dead.
这里情况怎么样 现状如何
How's it going up here? What's the status?
另一间病房也没声音了 我想我们是唯一幸存的一间
Nothing but silence from the other wards. I think we're the only ones left.
我一直在尝试覆盖封锁
I've been trying to override the quarantine.
如果我能发信号到新纽约
If I can trip a signal over to New New York,
他们就能派来一支秘密行动小组
they can send a private executive squad.
你不能这样做 如果他们强行进入 他们会破坏隔离的
You can't do that. If they forced entry, they'd break quarantine.
我不要死在这里
I am not dying in here.
我们不能让任何一点疾病外泄
We can't let a single particle of disease get out.
那城市有一千万人口 他们全都会冒风险 马上关掉
There's 10 million people in that city, they'd all be at risk. Now turn that off.
除非我能出去
Not if it gets me out.
好吧 我必须得连你们一块阻止 很适合我
All right, fine. So I have to stop you lot as well. Suits me.
洛斯 海姆修女 所有人 抱歉 主教
Rose, Novice Hame, everyone! Excuse me, Your Grace.
把每一种疾病的静脉注射液给我 快
Get me the intravenous solutions for every single disease! Move it!
怎么样 这样行吗
How's that? Will that do?
我不知道 做什么
I don't know. Will it do for what?
电梯不能运作
The lifts aren't working...
动不了 那就另当别论了
Not moving, different thing.
我们走吧
Here we go.
你该不会是要…
But you're not going to...
你认为你在做什么
What do you think you're doing?
我要下去了
I'm going down.
过来
Come on.
再过一百万年也不行
Not in a million years.
我需要帮手 你觉得呢
I need another pair of hands. What do you think?
如果你那么渴望活着 为什么不活的刺激一点
If you're so desperate to stay alive, why don't you live a little?
把门封住
Seal the door!
救我
Help.
不
No!
你真是彻底疯了 我知道她为什么喜欢你了
You're completely mad. I can see why she likes you.
下去
Going down!
这倒是个减肥的好办法
Well, that's one way to lose weight.
听着 当我下令 你就握住控制杆
Now, listen. When I say so, take hold of that lever.
但下面依然隔离着 我们不能…
There's still a quarantine down there. We can't...
握住控制杆
Hold that lever!
我要调鸡尾酒 我自己也懂点医学
I'm cooking up a cocktail. I know a bit about medicine myself.
控制杆会回弹 你一定要控制住位置
Now, that lever's gonna resist, but keep it in position.
你无论如何也要抓稳
Hold on to it with everything you've got.
你呢
What about you?
我有个预约 医生该干活了
I've got an appointment. The Doctor is in.
我在这里面 过来
I'm in here! Come on!
不要告诉他们
Don't tell them!
拉住控制杆
Pull that lever!
过来找我 过来 我在这里 过来
DOCTOR: Come and get me! Come on. I'm in here! Come on!
开始消毒第一步
Commence stage one disinfection.
快 过来
Come and get me. Come on!
过来 过来
Come on. Come on.
他们所想要做的是传递下去
All they want to do is pass it on.
传递吧
Pass it on!
传递什么
Pass on what?
传递吧
Pass it on!
他们要传递什么 你杀了他们吗 所有人
What did they pass on? Did you kill them? All of them?
不 那是你的做事方式
No, that's your way of doing things.
我是医生 我要治好他们
I'm the Doctor and I cured them.
那就对了 来吧 甜心
That's right. Hey! There we go, sweetheart.
你去他那里吧 去吧 就是这样
Go to him. Go. That's it. That's it.
这是新的亚种生物 卡桑德拉 一种全新的生命形式
It's a new subspecies, Cassandra. A brand-new form of life.
新人类 看看他们 看啊
New humans. Look at them! Look!
在猫的控制下 一直活在黑暗之中 靠管子生活
Run by cats, kept in the dark, fed by tubes,
但是现在完完全全活过来了
but completely, completely alive!
你不能否认他们 因为你也帮忙创造了他们
You can't deny them 'cause you helped create them.
人类总是不停的发展
The human race just keeps on going.
不停的改变 生命总会绽放
Keeps on changing. Life will out.
哈
Ha!
我们是新纽约警察 请远离淋浴
MAN: This is the NNYPD. Please step away from the shuttles.
所有员工请即刻向警官自首
All staff will present themselves to the officers for immediate arrest.
重复 即刻自首
I repeat. Immediate arrest.
所有新型生命都必须登记并带去护理
All new life forms will be catalogued and taken into care.
医院的所有访客都请到NNYPD录口供
All visitors to the hospital will be required to make a statement to the NNYPD.
伯欧之脸
The Face of Boe!
你不是快要死了吗
You were supposed to be dying.
今天还有更好的事要做 死亡可以等待
There are better things to do today. Dying can wait.
噢 我讨厌心灵感应
Oh, I hate telepathy.
真合我意 满脑子都是大脸
just what I need, a head full of big-face.
嘘
Shh!
我已经厌倦宇宙了 博士
I had grown tired with the universe, Doctor,
但你教会我重新看待它
but you have taught me to look at it anew.
有许多传说 你知道
There are legends, you know,
说你有几百万岁了
saying that you're millions of years old.
那是不可能的
Well, now, that would be impossible.
可不是吗
DOCTOR: Wouldn't it just?
我记得你有什么东西想告诉我
I got the impression there was something you wanted to tell me.
一个大秘密
A great secret.
传说是这样说的
So the legend says.
可以迟点告诉你
It can wait.
噢 非得这样吗
Oh, does it have to?
我们还会再见面的 博士 第三次也是最后一次
We shall meet again, Doctor, for the third time, for the last time,
到时就会真相大白了
and the truth shall be told.
直到那天…
Until that day...
这个关子卖得好
That is enigmatic.
这…这真是教科书式的卖关子
That is...that is textbook enigmatic.
现在到你了
And now for you.
但是一切都很圆满 一切都很好 你不能就这样放了我吗
But everything's happy. Everything's fine. Can't you just leave me?
你活得够久了
You've lived long enough.
离开洛斯 一切结束了 卡桑德拉
Leave that body and end it, Cassandra.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
没人想
No one does.
帮我
Help me.
我不能
I can't.
主人
Mistress...
你还活着
Oh! You're alive!
为了你 我死里逃生 主人
I kept myself safe for you, mistress.
身体
A body!
不仅如此 还是个志愿者
And not just that. A volunteer!
你敢 他的生命属于自己
Don't you dare! He's got a life of his own.
但是我崇拜主人
But I worship the mistress.
我欢迎她
I welcome her.
你不能 卡桑德拉 你…
You can't, Cassandra. You...
你还好吗
Oh! You all right?
还好吗
Okay?
没事
Yeah.
你好
Hello.
你好 欢迎回来
Hello. Welcome back.
噢 上帝啊 我走路歪歪扭扭的
Oh, sweet Lord! I'm a walking doodle.
你不能待在那里 对不起卡桑德拉 这对他不公平
You can't stay in there. I'm sorry, Cassandra, but that's not fair.
我可以带你去个城市 他们能为你建个皮肤容器
I can take you to the city. They can build you a skin-tank,
然后为你的所作所为接受审判
and you can stand trial for what you've done.
那还真够戏剧性的
Well, that would be rather dramatic.
那或者我最佳时机 当然是我最佳身份
Possibly my finest hour, and certainly my finest hat.
但恐怕我们没有时间了
But I'm afraid we don't have time.
可怜的阿奇 他只有半条命
Poor little Chip, he's only a half-life.
他经历了太多了 他的心脏跳得好快
And he's been through so much. His heart is racing so.
他正在衰竭 我觉得他只能持续…
He's failing. I don't think he's going to last...
你没事吧
You all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
我快要死了
I'm dying.
但没关系
But that's fine.
我能带你去那个城市
I can take you to the city.
不 不用了
No, you won't.
这星球一切都是新的
Everything's new on this planet.
已经没有地方能容纳我和阿奇了
There's no place for Chip and me anymore.
你是对的 博士
You were right, Doctor.
是时侯结束了
It's time to die.
这是好事
And that's good.
来吧 我还能帮你最后一件事
Come on, there's one last thing I can do.
噢不要 快停下
CASSANDRA: Oh, no don't!
那显然不是真的
That's simply not true.
可能性太小了 埃及太阴沉了
And believe me, it was so dismal.
还有蚊子 我不能告诉你…
And the mosquitoes, I can't tell you. They were...
谢谢
Thank you.
去吧 别回头
just go. And don't look back.
好运
Good luck.
你真见到他们了 你中招了 别说是我说的
And if you actually see them, you're shot! But don't quote me on that.
回头见
A bientot.
打扰了 卡桑德拉女士
Excuse me, the Lady Cassandra?
抱歉 我不需要任何东西 我很好 谢谢
I'm sorry, I don't need anything right now. I'm fine, thank you.
不 我只是想说 你很漂亮
No, I just wanted to say... you look beautiful.
嘴真甜 你这奇怪的小家伙
Well. That's very kind, you strange little thing.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
我是真心的
I mean it.
你看起来…
You look...
很美
so beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
噢 天啊 你没事吧 怎么了 怎么回事
Oh, my Lord. Are you all right? What is it? What's wrong?
找人来帮帮忙
Someone get some help!
快叫医生来 快 他是谁
Call a medic or something, quickly.
我不知道 我刚向我走过来
I don't know, he just came up to me.
甚至不知道他的名字
Don't even know his name.
他就倒下了 我想他快要死了 找人来帮忙
He just collapsed. I think he's dying. Someone do something!
我在这里 亲爱的 没事的
I've got you, sweetheart. It's all right. There you are.
你坚持住 我抱着你
There you are. I've got you.
一切都会好的
It'll be alright. There, there.
可怜的小东西
You poor little thing.
让我介绍一下殿下 维多利亚女王
Might I introduce Her Majesty Queen Victoria?
每到月圆之时 嚎叫之声环绕整个山谷
MAN: Every full moon, the howling rings through the valley.
那男人变成了动物
This is a man who becomes an animal.
狼人
A werewolf?
那不可能是只真狼
WOMAN: But it can't be an actual wolf.
子弹没用的
Bullets can't stop it!